<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ADB on Thamaraimanalan M - Portfolio</title><link>https://thamaraimanalan.tech/tags/adb/</link><description>Recent content in ADB on Thamaraimanalan M - Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thamaraimanalan.tech/tags/adb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Android Debloater Python Script</title><link>https://thamaraimanalan.tech/blogs/android-debloater-python-script/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thamaraimanalan.tech/blogs/android-debloater-python-script/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Developed a Python script that automates the removal of system apps from Android devices. This was born out of frustration with bloatware on Android phones and wanting to clean them up programmatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The script uses ADB (Android Debug Bridge) to communicate with Android devices and remove unwanted system applications that can&amp;rsquo;t normally be uninstalled through the regular interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project taught me about ADB protocol, and how to build useful automation tools. It also reinforced my Python skills, especially working with subprocess management and command-line tools.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Droid Debloat - Qt Desktop Application</title><link>https://thamaraimanalan.tech/blogs/droid-debloat-qt-desktop-application/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thamaraimanalan.tech/blogs/droid-debloat-qt-desktop-application/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Droid Debloat is a desktop application I built using the Qt Framework to help users remove unwanted system apps (bloatware) from their Android devices. This project was born out of my own frustration with the amount of pre-installed apps that come with Android devices and can&amp;rsquo;t be easily removed through normal means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-problem"&gt;The Problem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most Android devices come pre-loaded with numerous system apps that users might not want or need. These apps often can&amp;rsquo;t be uninstalled through the regular interface, leading to cluttered devices and wasted storage space.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>