<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Qt Framework on Thamaraimanalan M - Portfolio</title><link>/tags/qt-framework/</link><description>Recent content in Qt Framework on Thamaraimanalan M - Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/qt-framework/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>WiFi Jammer - Linux Application</title><link>/blogs/wifi-jammer-linux-application/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blogs/wifi-jammer-linux-application/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Built a WiFi jammer application for Linux that can jam WiFi access points. This was a learning project to understand network security concepts and GUI Development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application targets WiFi access points and disrupts their normal operation. It taught me a lot about network protocols, wireless security, and how networks can be vulnerable to certain types of attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="key-features"&gt;Key features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux-based WiFi jamming functionality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy GUI with Qt Framework&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project helped me understand the importance of network security and how to protect against such attacks. It&amp;rsquo;s important to note this should only be used for educational purposes and on networks you own or have permission to test.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Qt Champion 2024 - 3rd Place in Global Qt-athon Competition</title><link>/blogs/qt-champion-2024-third-place/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blogs/qt-champion-2024-third-place/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Thrilled to announce that I achieved 3rd place in the Qt-athon 2024 competition! This global event organized by Qt Group brought together developers from around the world to showcase their Qt framework expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The competition challenged participants to build innovative applications using Qt framework, pushing the boundaries of what&amp;rsquo;s possible with cross-platform development. My project focused on creating a sophisticated GUI application that demonstrated both technical prowess and user experience design.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Droid Debloat - Qt Desktop Application</title><link>/blogs/droid-debloat-qt-desktop-application/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blogs/droid-debloat-qt-desktop-application/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Droid Debloat is a desktop application I built using the Qt Framework to help users remove unwanted system apps (bloatware) from their Android devices. This project was born out of my own frustration with the amount of pre-installed apps that come with Android devices and can&amp;rsquo;t be easily removed through normal means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-problem"&gt;The Problem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most Android devices come pre-loaded with numerous system apps that users might not want or need. These apps often can&amp;rsquo;t be uninstalled through the regular interface, leading to cluttered devices and wasted storage space.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>